A Guide to the Virginia Counselors Association records, 1930-1997
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Counselors Association, 1930-1997
The Library of Virginia
30684
8.55 cu. ft. and 20 boxes
Virginia Counselors Association
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Virginia Counselors Association
Custodial History
Accessions 31489, 31646, 31707, 32016, 32180, 33334, 33810, 34368, 35015, 36715, and 38815 are filed with accession 30684.
Historical Information
Founded in Richmond, Virginia, in 1930, the organization is the state branch of the American Personnel and Guidance Association, whose national headquarters are in Falls Church, Virginia. The organization was called the Virginia Association of Guidance and Personnel Workers up to 1956, and then became the Virginia Personnel and Guidance Association. In 1981, the organization changed its name to the Virginia Counselors Association. Organized to lobby the state legislature and to promote the continued elevation of the status of the counseling profession and the professional development of its members.
Scope and Content
Records, 1930-1997, of the Virginia Counselors Association concerning the organization, goals, and operations of the organization and containing agendas; annual, board, and executive meeting minutes; chapter and committee reports; correspondence; histories; membership lists; newsletters; resolutions; and miscellaneous subject files. There is also information relating to the Virginia Elementary School Guidance and Counseling Act of 1979, as well as tapes of radio public service announcements produced by the Stratford chapter.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I: Administrative files.
Series II: Committee/Board Meeting minutes, 1933-1934, 1948-1997.
Series III: Annual Conferences and Meetings, 1932-1996.
Series IV: Reports, 1932-1994.
Series V: Secretary's files, 1983-1996.
Series VI: Correspondence, 1942-1987.
Series VII: Lists and Directories of Officers and Members, 1930-1994.
Series VIII: Elementary School Guidance and Counseling Act of 1979, 1976-1981.
Series IX: Gertrude D. Lewis files.
Series X: Publications, 1948-1994
Series XI: Miscellaneous files
Series XII: Audio Tapes, 1981-1982
Contents List
- Series I: Administrative files., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  Administrative files include articles of incorporation and related papers, constitution and by-laws, organizational handbooks and guidelines, policies, and an organization history from 1930 to 1969.
  - Records concerning incorporation, 1966, 1970. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles of incorporation and related materials, 1970, 1976. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Constitutions and by-laws, 1948-1972. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Organizational handbook and guidelines, 1967. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Organizational handbook and guidelines, 1975 (2 copies). (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Organizational handbook and guidelines, 1976. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Handbook (draft), 1982. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Handbook, 1990. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Policies, 1981. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Policy manual, 1994. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History of the Virginia Personnel and Guidance Association 1930-1969, 1970. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Certificates, 1957, 1962, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II: Committee/Board Meeting minutes, 1933-1934, 1948-1997., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 1-3)
  Committee/Board Meeting minutes, 1933-1934, 1948-1997, contain the minutes of the Executive Committee and the Board of Directors meetings, and related papers.
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1933-1934, 1948-1950, 1952-1958. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1959-1962. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1963-1966. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1967. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1968. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1969-1970. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 1971. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Executive Board/Committee meeting minutes, 1972. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Executive Board meeting minutes, 1973. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Executive Board and Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1974. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1975-1976. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Executive Committee and Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1977-1978. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1979-1981 (for 19 September meeting, see next folder). (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 19 September 1980. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1981-1984. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Board meeting minutes, 1985-1986. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1987. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1988. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meeting minutes, April-May 1989. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Executive Committee and Board of Directors meeting minutes, July-October 1989. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meeting minutes, November 1989-1990. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1993. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1994. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1996. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee meeting minutes, 1997. (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Series III: Annual Conferences and Meetings, 1932-1996., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 3-5)
  Annual Conferences, Conventions, and Meetings, 1932-1996, contain articles, brochures, correspondence, minutes, programs, registration forms, reports, speeches, surveys, and other papers relating to annual meetings, conferences, and conventions.
  - Annual meetings, 1932-1939. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Annual meetings, 1940-1949. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Annual conference, 1950-1951. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Annual conference, 1952. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Annual conference and meeting, 1953. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Annual meetings and conferences, 1954-1956. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Annual conference and meeting, 1957. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Annual conferences and meetings, 1958-1959. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Annual convention, 1960-1961. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Annual conferences, 1962-1964. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Annual conferences and meetings, 1965-1966. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Annual convention and meeting, 1967. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Annual convention and meeting, 1968. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Annual conference and meeting, 1969. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Annual convention and meeting, 1970. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Annual convention and meeting--papers, 1970. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Annual convention and meeting--study, 1970. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Annual conference/convention and meeting, 1971. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Annual conference/convention and meeting, 1972. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Annual convention and meeting, 1973. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Annual convention and meeting, 1974. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Annual convention and meeting, 1975. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Annual convention and meeting, 1976. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Annual convention and meeting, 1977. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Annual conventions and meetings, 1978-1979. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Annual conventions and meetings, 1981-1983, 1986-1988. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Annual convention, 1989. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Annual conventions, 1990, 1992-1993. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Annual conventions and meetings, 1995-1996. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - VCA Convention Task Force, 1991. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Reports, 1932-1994., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 5-7)
  Reports, 1932-1994, contain the reports of chapters, committees, divisions, and treasurers of the organization detailing its operations and goals. Papers also include budgets, by-laws, correspondence, minutes, and resolutions.
  - Committee reports and resolutions, 1950, 1952-1953, 1955, 1960-1963, 1965-1968. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Committee reports and resolutions, 1969-1970. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Committee reports and resolutions, 1971-1974. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Committee reports and resolutions, 1975-1979. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Treasurer's and membership reports, 1932-1941, 1944, 1946, 1948-1949, 1952-1953, 1957-1967. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer's and membership reports, 1967-1978. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Chapter annual reports, minutes, and correspondence, 1949-1950, 1958-1963, 1965-1966, 1968, 1972-1976. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Chapter annual reports, minutes, and correspondence, 1976-1979. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Division annual reports, by-laws, and correspondence, 1970-1979. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Reports, 1980. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Reports, 1981-1982. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Report and recommendations for Action Retrenchment Advisory Committee, 1982. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Reports, 1983-1984. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Reports, 1988. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Reports, 1989. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Reports, 1990. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Reports, 1993-1994. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Series V: Secretary's files, 1983-1996., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 7-9)
  Secretary's files, 1983-1996, include agendas, brochures, budgets, calendars, correspondence, directories, handbooks, journals, lists, manuals, minutes, newsletters, notebooks, photographs, plans, programs, reports, and schedules.
  - Handbook and ethics committee manual, 1983, 1990. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Papers, March-June 1990. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - State Special Education Advisory Report, May 1990. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Papers, July-December 1990. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Papers, January-July 1991. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Papers, August-October 1991. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Papers, November 1991-March 1992. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Secretary's notebook--all-member business meetings, 1995-1996. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Secretary's notebook--Board of Directors meetings, 1995. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Secretary's notebook--Board of Directors meetings, 1996. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Secretary's notebook--calendar and Board of Directors membership list, 1995-1996. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Secretary's notebook--correspondence, 1995-1996. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Secretary's notebook--Executive Committee meetings, 1995-1996. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Secretary's notebook--miscellaneous, 1995-1996. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Printed materials--journals and newsletters, 1990-1991. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Membership directory and brochures, 1991, no date. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, no date. (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Series VI: Correspondence, 1942-1987., Extent: 1 box. (Box 9)
  Correspondence, 1942-1987, contains correspondence to and from the Virginia Counselors Association (Virginia Personnel and Guidance Association) concerning the goals and operations of the organization. Papers include correspondence from its parent organization, the American Personnel and Guidance Association, and a note from Lyndon B. Johnson (1908-1973).
  - Correspondence, 1942, 1950-1954. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1958. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1966. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1969. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1978. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1987. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - american Personnel and Guidance Association correspondence and memoranda, 1956-1972. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson note, 1972. (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Series VII: Lists and Directories of Officers and Members, 1930-1994., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 10-11)
  Lists and Directories of Officers and Members, 1930-1994, contain membership rosters, lists of officers, and organization and member directories.
  - Lists of officers, 1930-1950, 1953-1962, 1964-1974, 1977-1979. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Officers list, 1979-1982. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors list, 1985-1986. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Chapter presidents, 1988-1989. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors list, 1993-1994. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Membership lists, 1934-1936, 1939-1942, 1946, 1949-1950. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Membership lists, 1950-1953. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Membership lists, 1953-1958. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Membership lists, 1960-1964, 1966-1967. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Membership lists, 1967-1969. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Membership lists, 1970-1973. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Membership lists, 1977. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Directories, 1961-1962. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Directories, 1964. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Directory, 1966-1967 (2 copies). (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Directory, 1971-1972 (2 copies). (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Directory, 1972-1973 (2 copies). (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Directory, 1978. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Directory, 1980. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Directory, 1981. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Directory, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Directory, 1994. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Directory--Richmond Personnel and Guidance Association, 1961. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Directory--Richmond Personnel and Guidance Association, 1963. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Directory--Richmond Personnel and Guidance Association, 1964-1965. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Directory--Roanoke Area Counselors Association,. (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Series VIII: Elementary School Guidance and Counseling Act of 1979, 1976-1981., Extent: 11-13. (Box 3)
  Elementary School Guidance and Counseling Act of 1979, 1976-1981, contains articles, awards, budgets, bulletins, correspondence, labels, legislation, lists, plans, programs, statements, surveys, and other papers concerning the Elementary School Guidance and Counseling Act of 1979.
  - ACES (Association for Counselor Education) and ASCA (American School Counselor Association) joint statement on elementary school counselor,. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - APGA program at Las Vegas, Nevada, 2-5 April 1979. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Survey forms and original covering letter, 1980. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - List of state divisions--ASCA, 1978-1979. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - National Elementary Guidance--labels. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Letters responding to proposal for legislation, 1978-1980. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Survey #1--National Elementary Guidance legislation, November 1979. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Survey #2--National Elementary School Guidance legislation, 1979-1980. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Budgets and plans of action, mission statement for elementary guidance, 1978-1979. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Record of Virginia Personnel and Guidance Association funds spent, 1978. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Report from Borwn and Cook to APGA and ASCA, 18 July 1978. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Birth of a Bill--first draft, correspondence, etc., 1978-1979. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Copies of bulletins to the nation and copies of form letter to those offering help, 1978-1980. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Article published in The School Psychologist, 1979. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Letter of approval to Dr. Riehm and letters to state department personnel and to local supervisor of guidance, 1978-1979. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Co-sponsors of HR 5477, 1980. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Letters from Pat Hooper, J. Thompson, Billie Jackson, 1979-1981. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Letters received and answered--general information and statements made Augusta County project, 1977-1981. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Letters received and sent, 1977-1978. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Letters received and sent, 1979. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Letters received and sent, 1980. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - News releases (ASCA) and congratulatory letters, 1978-1980. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Printed material. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - State Senate resolution #132: state elementary guidance bill, 1979-1980. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Letters of recommendations--awards--J. R. Cook, 1976-1978. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - APGA Distinguished Legislative Service Award for Jeanette Brown and John R. Cook, 1979. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - SACES (Southern Association for Counselor Education and Supervision) Award, 1979. (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Series IX: Gertrude D. Lewis files., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 14-15)
  Gertrude D. Lewis files contain papers of Gertrude D. Lewis (1916-2000) of Culpeper, Virginia, who worked as a high school guidance counselor supervisor for the state department of education. Papers are related to the projects, organizations, and other matters with which she was involved.
  - ACES, 1976-1977. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - CACO (Clusters Approach to Career Orientation) project, 1975-1978. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Career decision-making, 1977. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Carroll County career development project, 1975. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Career development--curriculum guides, 1974. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Career Development--NVGA position paper and ACES position paper, 1975-1978. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Career guidance--activities (folder 1 of 3). (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Career guidance--activities (folder 2 of 3). (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Career guidance--activities (folder 3 of 3). (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Career information center, 1974-1976. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - College day program, 1978. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - College scholarships and financing, 1977. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Computer assisted guidance, 1974-1977. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Counselor image, 1975. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Disruptive student, 1971-1978. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Drugs--counselors' responsibilities, 1973. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Elementary guidance (folder 1 of 2). (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Elementary guidance (folder 2 of 2). (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - ESEA Title IV, 1977-1978. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Films, filmstrips, 1976-1978. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Gifted, 1977. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Handicapped, 1977. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Objectives--guidance, 1973-1978. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Guidance objectives--mangement. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Para-professionals in guidance, 1974. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Senior survey and ninth grade survey, 1976-1977. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Sex education, 1977. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Special education, 1977. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Value clarification. (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Series X: Publications, 1948-1994., Extent: 1 box. (Box 16)
  Publications, 1948-1994, includes the newsletters of the Virginia Personnel and Guidance Association and the Virginia Counselors Association, including the titles The Relator and The Virginia Counselor; VPGA and VCA journals; organization brochures; other publications; and newspaper clippings.
  - Newsletters, 1948, 1950. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Newsletters, 1956-1959. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, 1960-1962. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, 1963-1967. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Newsletters, 1968-1970. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Newsletters, 1971-1973. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - The Relator,1973-1974. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - The Relator,1975-1978. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The Relator,1978-1979. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - The Relator,1984-1988. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - The Relator,1989. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - The Virginia Counselor,1993-1994. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Work and Training,1950-1951. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Virginia Personnel and Guidance Journal,1973. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Personnel and Guidance Journal,1974. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Personnel and Guidance Journal,1975-1976. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Counselors Journal,1987. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Counsors Journal,1994. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Reach Out. (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Brochures: state organization. (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Brochures: local chapters. (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - News clippings, 1948-1973. (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Series XI: Miscellaneous files., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 17-18)
  Miscellaneous files contain papers relating to VPGA and VCA goals and operations, including committees, workshops, awards, public relations and other subjects. Also contain publications, directories, and papers of other organizations that the VCA often worked with or had the same interests. Also contain the VPGA seal and the VPGA career service award plaque.
  - Ethics committee responsibilities and procedures, 1982-1983. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Implementing ethical standards: development of a model program for state branches of APGA,1981. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - A Guide for public relations personnel, 1979. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Career service award, 1969-1975. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - The counselor and the law workshop, 1970. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Government relations workshop. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Association for Non-white Concerns in Personnel and Guidance of the Virginia Counselors Association, 1981. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Richmond Personnel and Guidance Association minutes, 17 February 1972. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Lynchburg Area Counselors Association, 1990. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - The Accrediting Commission for Business Schools: Directory of Accredited Institutions and Operating Criteria, 1966-1967. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - American Association for Counseling and Development papers, 1988, 1991. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - American School Counselors Association professional recognition award for John R. Cook, 1979 (folder 1 of 2). (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - American School Counselors Association professional recognition award for John R. Cook, 1979 (folder 2 of 2). (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - The Bookmen's Association of Virginia directory, 1962-1963. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Charter Westbrook Hospital Horizons,1984. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - House of Representatives The Working Congress,1976. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Juvenile Delinquency Prevention Program, Division of Youth Services--Virginia Department of Corrections Prevention Profiles,. (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - National Vocational Guidance Association papers, 1950, 1962-1963, 1969. (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - State Board of Vocational Education: Vocational Education in Virginia,. (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Virginia Association for Counselor Education and Supervision certificate, 7 April 1971. (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Address to Virginia Association of Vocational Guidance, 23 October 1952. (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Virginia College Personnel Association papers, 1981, 1989. (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Virginia Elementary School Counselors Association papers, 1979-1980. (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Virginia Mental Health Counselors Association conference, 15 July 1983. (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Virginia Psychological Association directory, 1962-1963. (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Virginia School Counselors Association newsletter, 1974. (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Virginia School Mental Health Coalition papers, 1992. (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Virginia State Advisory Council on Vocational Education: 14th annual evaluation report, 1983. (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Virginia State Board of Education guidance newsletter, 1952, 1956, 1965-1966. (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1965, 1970, 197[-]. (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1979-1982, 198[-]. (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1989. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1990-1992. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Miscellanous papers, 1993, 199[-]. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - VPGA seal. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - VPGA career service award, 1964-1974. (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Series XII: Audio tapes, 1981-1982., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 19-20)
  Audio tapes, 1981-1982, contain copies of four different public service announcements concerning counselors. PSAs were made by the Stratford chapter of the VPGA/VCA. A digital copy of these recordings was made in January 2015, and a CD-R containing all four was added to Box 20.
  - Audio tapes #1-#3, 1981. (Box 19)
  - Audio tapes #4, 1982. (Box 20)